So, I'm joined with Robert from Airbnb.
坐我对面的是 Airbnb 的 Robert
Robert, thanks so much for joining us.
Robert 欢迎加入我们
Thank you for having me.
感谢邀请
Can you first, maybe give us some advice,
你能给我们一些入门数据科学领域的建议嘛？
about how you would go about breaking into the field of data science?
比如说 你当时是如何开始的？
A lot of our students are just starting out.
因为我们很多的同学正在准备踏入数据科学这个领域
I would say the first thing is,
我觉得 第一件重要的事情
focus on the fundamentals.
就是做好打好基础
I think this is a relatively new field and there's sort of new innovations,
数据科学是一个相对比较新的领域
new technology coming out,
每天都会有些新的创新和技术
pretty much like every week.
基本上是每星期都有
So, it's almost impossible to kind of keep up with things.
所以 基本上不可能一直都能跟得上技术的脚步
You can always pick up more stuff if you have good fundamentals.
但如果你本身基础就比较好 学起来就会很快
Yeah, so what are the fundamental areas that you would push toward?
那你说的基础主要是指哪些呢
Yes, that's a good question. Just basic knowledge around statistics,
这是个很好的问题 我觉得 主要是跟统计学相关的基础知识
and basic working knowledge of just dealing with computers.
计算机相关的基础知识
So, these could be things like,
比如说
knowing how to query data,
如何查询数据
knowing how to interact with a command line tool.
如何使用命令行
Can we talk a little bit about the different roles of data scientists, on your teams?
可以谈一谈你们团队中的不同的数据科学家角色吗
What do they do?
他们具体都做什么
What differentiates their skillset?
他们在技术储备上有什么不同
I don't know if you're a part of hiring,
我不知道你自己会不会招聘数据科学家
but what are those things that you look for when you're hiring
如果有 你会比较看重哪些特质
candidates that fall into certain data science teams?
如何把他们归类到相应的数据科学家角色中
Yeah, we have physicists, former physicists,
没有问题 我们有物理学家 或者说曾经的物理学家
we have former social scientists,
我们有来自社会学
we have people who study statistics,
统计学 计算机 运筹学
computer science, operations research,
背景的人
and it's kind of all over the place.
但他们现在都在做数据科学
I think the common theme is that people have spent a lot of time doing analytical works,
我觉得他们的共性就是曾经都花很多的时间在分析类的工作上
and they're very analytical-driven and very data-driven.
他们都是非常分析驱动或者说数据驱动的类型
So, that's like the whole culture?
你们整个公司文化都是这样的吧？
That's the whole culture. Those are the things that we really look for.
是的 这也属于公司文化 我们会看重某些能力
So, we're not really looking at you know someone
但我们并不会特别在意
who's graduated from a particular score or degree.
一个求职者的分数或学位
But let me describe a little bit how we think about it at Airbnb.
让我具体来说明一下 Airbnb 的情况
At Airbnb we have three tracks;
在 Airbnb 我们有三种类型的数据科学家：
the first track is called Analytics.
第一种是分析类的
Typically these are people who focus a lot on business intelligence,
他们的工作主要是跟商业智能有关
trying to understand the trends of the business,
需要去理解目前商业的趋势
how we're doing as a business.
当下的运营情况
So, it's generally quite high level and
通常都是高层次问题
your stakeholders are generally people who are decision makers.
他们直接汇报的人 主要都是一些做决策的高层管理人士
So, it could be product managers,
比如 产品经理
it could be the lead of entire product work.
也可能是负责整个产品的人
The type of work that you do typically
这种类型的工作
are sort of a little bit more high level. So that's Analytics.
层次一般都比较高 这就是分析类的数据科学家
Then we have people who are on an inference track.
我们还有预测类的数据科学家
For inference people, we typically do a lot of experiment design.
这类人一般会做实验设计
You typically work very closely with a full-stack team
他们一般跟软件开发团队的人合作非常紧密
where that team is responsible for trying out different product iterations.
因为他们要负责不断地更新和迭代产品
It's very common for tech companies now day to run AB tests.
如今的科技公司 很多都做 AB 测试
So, data scientists are very valuable in helping and design the experiment set up,
数据科学家对于设计好的实验是非常重要的
determining how long the experiment should be run for and making sure that we're tracking
比如说一个实验要做多久 要跟踪哪些指标
the right metric so we can understand the behavioral change
才能有助于理解用户的行为
of the new product versus the old product,
观察他们的行为是如何随着产品的更新而变化的
and in doing product analytics.
他们也做一些产品分析
I think this is true for both inference and analytics.
我觉得他们的工作里预测和分析都有
There's a lot of analyses around how users are actually using our products.
有关用户是如何使用我们产品的 我们就可以做很多的分析
Then we have the third track, which is algorithm.
最后我们还有第三条线路是算法类
This is a track where people spend a lot of time building data products.
这条线上的人 会花很多的时间来构建数据产品
So, it could be something like
比如说一个推荐引擎
a recommendation engine or it could be an image model that does image classification.
比如说一个图片分类的模型
So, they typically focus more on
所以他们的侧重点是建模
specific modelling projects or
和构建数据产品
data products rather than trying to explain the trend of the business.
而不是去解释 目前商业的趋势
But I will say the tracking system is more of a guidance.
不过 我必须得说 我们很多人都是同时做
I will say a lot of people at Airbnb do cross-works.
很多类型的工作
I certainly have done pretty much all tracks.
比如说 我就基本上做过所有类型的数据工作
I think that's kind of the nature of working as a data scientist which
但我觉得 这大概也是数据科学工作的本质吧
is depending on what product we're building,
取决于你正在构建的数据产品
you would try to use the right tool to solve that problem.
你需要采用合适的工具解决相应的问题
That tool could be analytics,
这些工具可能是分析类的
could be experiment design, could be modelling.
实验设计类的 还有就是建模类的
So, being able to kind of juggle around with
针对不同的问题 判断使用不同的工具
the different tools in your tool set is an important skill to have.
我认为 是一项非常重要的技能
Cool.
好的